Guide to the Alexander Dallin Papers SC1216
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alexander Dallin papers
1940-1999
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lapidus, Gail W.
Dallin, Alexander.
SC1216
18 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes Dallin's research materials, lecture and presentation materials, computer media, and audiovisual materials.
Biographical / Historical
Alexander Dallin (1924-2000) was the Raymond A. Spruance Professor of International History at Stanford and served as Director for the Center for Russian and East European Studies. Dallin was an American historian, political scientist, and international relations scholar.Dallin He earned a bachelor's degree in social science from City College of New York in 1947 and master's and doctoral degrees in history from Columbia University in 1948 and 1953.
Russia (Federation) -- History.; russian studies; Russia (Federation) -- Politics and government.; Russian -- History; Lapidus, Gail W.; Dallin, Alexander.
- Research Material
  - Soviet Union/Eastern Bloc (Box 1, Box 6, Box 3, Box 2)
  - Soviet Studies Programs (Box 3)
- Computer Media
- Publications
  - Final manuscript, 1999
  - France, 1939-1940
- Lectures and Presentations
- Personal
  - S.S. Excalibur List of Passengers, 1941
- Audiovisual Material
  - Alexander Sakharov: His Legacy Ten Years Later, 1999
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-043
  - Stanford University, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CV, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New Democracy Fellows Program at Stanford, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Milton Loventhal San Jose State University, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bill and Hillary Clinton photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lia Andler, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-033
  - Alexander Dallin Naturalization Certificate (digital scan), 1943